Communication and being able to
communicate powerfully is one of the
best ways to reach your goals and to do
the things that you want to do in your
business. And today I want to talk about
how to use chat GPT to help you do that
better. This is one of the things that
listen I think was really taboo when AI
first came out. I think people were like
well you don't want to lose your voice.
You don't want AI replacing your voice
or things like that. But I think we miss
the fact that you can use AI to help you
communicate your thoughts and feelings
better. Not all of us know how to say
the stuff that we're feeling. Not all of
us know how to communicate and
articulate that stuff as it comes to
mind. And yet learning how to
communicate and articulate things
powerfully is one of the best things
that you can do. And chat GPT can help
guide you in that direction. Because
this is about business. I want to help
you if you're in business, how to be
able to utilize chat GPT to be able to
get more sales, get more clients, and
work with more people that you want to
work with long term. And I do this all
the time in different conversations,
different interactions. I'm going to
give you a couple of different examples
of how this might look from my own life
that you can use in chat GBT. Okay,
number one, like let's say that you met
somebody at the store somewhere and I
use chat GBT five thinking. This is on
the pro version of Chess or no, the plus
version of Chat GPT, the $20 a month
version. Let's say that you met somebody
at the grocery store and you want to be
able to
reconnect with them and because they
were a good fit for what you offer in
your business, you want to segue the
conversation to be around your business.
Actually pre-wrote this prompt earlier.
Um,
I just met somebody at the grocery
store. exchange numbers. They're a
coach. Good fit for what I offer.
There's a lot of typos here, but that's
okay. I have a podcast, free resources,
videos, YouTube, and do consulting. They
gave me their number. Give me a message
I could send to re-engage. A script of
how to lead the conversation towards
them possibly working with me. Okay. So,
this is one example of how you might do
this.
And what it's doing is it's going to go
and process through how to do that and
different ways of things that you could
text them, what you could say when you
see them and otherwise. Okay. So, while
that's loading, another scenario is
let's say that you
have a car and you discovered an issue
with the car and there's damage that was
undisclosed when you purchased the
vehicle and you know that the person who
sold it to you, the dealership should
end up paying for it. I bought a car
recently with frame damage. I want to go
back to the selling dealership in Texas
to request they pay for repairs. Give me
a script to be able to do this.
Okay,
so there's an example. Let's go back to
our previous example right here and
let's look at what this tells us. So we
got a couple of different versions of
this. The re-engagement script. Okay.
Hey, Jeremiah from the grocery line.
Loved our chat.
Um, no, I don't like that one. Tiny
anchor.
Um,
so I so I want to just re engage a
conversation and then a one- on-one
script of how to take things to that
next level.
Okay. See that this is taking this.
Okay. So, that's helping us there.
Here's another example. I'm just going
to I'm going to load up these examples
because it's thinking through it. Um,
I want to talk to my wife about
going out of town this weekend and
suggest we go to Waco with the kids.
How would I approach this? Now, I
wouldn't necessarily use it for that
conversation. I would rather just ask
her. But this is just an example of how
you can use chatbt. Some of you all
might be rolling your eyes that I even
like put that in there. It's just an
example of how you might might use it in
that way. Okay, let's look at the
re-engagement right here. Okay, light
Jeremiah for the checkout. Fun meeting
you. Realize we never swapped links.
What's the best place to see your work?
This is great. Awesome.
Probably would leave off. I'll send mine
to
uh great bumping into you. I've got a
couple free resources.
Bridge reply.
Are you pushing right now to get more
eyeballs on something? One-on-one
script.
So glad we connected.
And so again,
I would keep the conversation more light
and sweet and not go right into it with
something like this. But these are some
ways that you could segue the
conversation to move things in the
middle of a conversation to move things
forward as ways to do that. for the car
repair. Hey, this is so and so. I bought
this post inspection. Discover this. It
wasn't disclosed. Please authorize to
pay for the repairs.
Is this the right person?
Okay. Forward this.
Um, if we can't resolve this informally,
I'll send a Texas Deceptive Trade
Practices Act
notice to pursue other remedies.
So, this gives you kind of an outline as
far as what you could do. And I actually
had to do this for a vehicle that I
purchased right here. Uh, I was dealing
with an issue with my roofers. I have a
roofer
who is asking for more money than
was agreed upon and believes
it's owed him for work he didn't do.
Give me a script to discuss this. And
again, I get it. Some of you might be
like, "This is ridiculous. You have to
ask AI to help you with these
conversations." That's what we're taught
and we're trained to think. But can I
tell you this? That learning about
persuasion, learning about conversation,
learning about how to communicate,
even if you just get one little nugget
from a little conver, like I'm not going
to be reading one of these scripts
verbatim. I don't. But I read through it
to help me then formulate how I would
communicate. Especially the one for the
car repair one would be something like
that. Okay.
Affirm and clear. Hey, let's hop on a
quick call today. I want to settle some
things on the invoice.
Hey there, just jumping on this to wrap
this up. Pay what's owed on our
agreement. I looked at the scope. It
does include doesn't include the extra
items you mentioned. Our agreement says
additional work requires a signed change
order.
uh by my ledger. We did this. Remaining
contract for completed work is this.
Uh if you believe there's additional
work outside the scope, email me a
packet of these items.
Push back. Here's some push back.
Materials cost more. We did more work
than the scope. You're withholding my
money. I'm ready to pay the contractual
balance. Agreed upon scope. This
protects both of us. I'll file a lean.
You're free to pursue other remedies.
I'll dispute any amount beyond the
contract. I prefer we avoid this. And
again, by the way, like I I literally
went through this process. It didn't
escalate like this. They were asking for
$60,000. They were only owed $30,000.
That's a big difference, okay, on my
roof repair with insurance. And I talked
to them and I said, "We will pay the
only the amount for the roof, not a
penny more." And they were like, "Okay,
great. We will make a separate invoice
with just those amounts." But this was
able to help me have that conversation
by being able to do this. Uh, let's see.
Suggesting a time with my wife, picking
a time with purpose. Ask for 10 15
minutes. Is now a good time to talk
about the weekend? Leave with care.
Signal that isn't a demand and you'll
carry the load.
Offer one to two easy options. Let's
see. I would probably more use this if
it was like going out with like friends
or something like that and her watching
the kids. I'll pack the kids snacks.
Confirm a stroller friendly plan and
book something with an easy exit.
We'll keep quiet blocks for you and
protect nap windows. Okay.
Um, let's say that you
I just had a great conversation with a
long-term client. Want to segue to them
joining me for a new offer that fits
what they are dealing with? write me a
script to text them about this after our
call. Okay,
this is another example of something
like this. And then I'm going to give
you one last example is I just had a
sales call with a potential client
and I want to write an email that is
excited about moving forward working
with them to build out their
art coaching offer and accomplish
their goal of 100 new students by March.
Okay. Might use something like that. I
had this conversation. I want to come up
with what to say in this email. All
right.
See, here's a text script. Longtime
client quick thought after our call.
Exactly what this is exactly my new
offer helps with. It helps with a
specific offer uh specific outcome in
time frame without common hassle.
Appreciate our chat. Given the situation
you described where you've been trying
to get your offer going, things like
that, I'd recommend
staying with me in my VIP program and
continuing forward so that you know what
to do so that I can come alongside you
and show you exactly what steps to take.
I do this all the time when I'm doing
conversations, when I'm texting clients,
when I'm writing them, when I'm DMing,
when I'm sending individualized emails,
and I'm using AI to help me communicate
exactly how to say these things.
Here's one for that art coaching. Loved
our call today. Your vision for art
coaching is spot on. I'm excited to
partner with you. See, it's affirmative.
It gives you scripts of what to say, how
to say it, how to put it together.
Again, this might not be the exact
deliverables.
Sometimes what I like to do, too, is I
might copy a conversation. I had a
client where I did a soft sales pitch
without a price on a conversation. I
pulled the transcript in cuz I recorded
it and I actually pulled the transcript
right into chat GPT and I told it, okay,
take this transcript and turn it into a
proposal email
and write me some bullet points for a
proposal video to send to the person.
And it literally closed the sale, made
$20,000 right off of that, right off the
bat. And so what I'm trying to show you
and trying to encourage you in
there are so many use cases and
scenarios for using chat GPT to help you
communicate as a better salesperson for
you to know how to say something better
that's more persuasive
because that's the difference maker
between just merely informing people
about what you have to offer and getting
them to actually make a purchase and to
buy from you. And so, listen, if you're
somebody who wants to take that business
to the next level, I'd love to work with
you in my Wealthy Coach Academy program.
Inside of that program, you can find a
link in the description below this
video. I help you know exactly what to
do in your business to get more clients
and to make more money by knowing what
to say, how to say it, how to put all
the pieces together, how to put an offer
together, how to build out your funnel,
how to build out your traffic,
and what to truly do strategically
that's going to get people on your email
list that you can close more of those
sales. And so again, I'd love to work
with you. I'd love to help you with
that. Click one of the links below.
We'll talk soon. kind of going.